# TRACEY REIS

# SOFTWARE ENGINEER

tracey.trepper@gmail.com 845-642-3575 New York, New York linkedin.com/in/tracey-reis https://github.com/tbtreppe www.traceyreis.com

### SUMMARY

Software Engineer who is passionate about creating products that focuses on the user experience and interface. Develops frontend and backend applications using programming languages such as HTML, CSS, Javascript, React.js, Python, Flask, Node.js, and Express. Collaboratively works with team members to ensure goals are established, and pair programming is utilized to solve rigorous problems.

## **EDUCATION**

Fullstack Certificate Springboard Software Engineering Bootcamp Frontend Certificate SheCodes Workshops BFA Textile Design Syracuse University

# **SKILLS**

#### PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES:

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python, APIs, AJAX, jQuery, Flask, SQL, PostgresQL, Data Structures, Algorithms, SQLAlchemy, React, Express, Node

#### **SOFTWARE/TOOLS:**

Microsoft Word, Microsoft Excel, Microsoft Powerpoint, Figma, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe Indesign

### **EXPERIENCE**

G-iii Calvin Klein, Sweater Designer

February 2017 - Current

G-iii Calvin Klein, Associate Sweater Designer

July 2014 - February 2017

Responsible for conceptualizing, designing, and overseeing the production of sweaters through market research and communication

- Research and collaborates with team members using agile values to ensure efficiency
- Collaboratively works with teams in office and abroad to maintain accuracy of products
- Utilizes Adobe photoshop and Illustrator to design wireframes and mock-ups.
- · Develops technical packages using Microsoft Excel with specific details to finalize requirements of garments
- Enhances design processes to maximize time and cost efficiency
- Leads project management meetings in order to reduce cost by 50%
- Guides and supports assistant through comprehensive training programs and ongoing mentorship

### Springboard Software Engineering Bootcamp, Software Engineer

April 2021 to November 2022

800+ hours of hands-on course material, with 1:1 industry expert mentor oversight, and completion of 4 in-depth portfolio projects. Mastered skills in front-end web development, back-end web development, databases, and data structures and algorithms.

- Studied databases and data structures and algorithms
- Coded javascript functions using ajax functions to create user prompts and web applications
- Learned pair programming skills in order to problem solve coding challenges

### **PROJECTS**

### What's in your kitchen? | https://whatsinyourkitchen.netlify.app

 A website where a user can find a recipe and mark it as a favorite by searching for an ingredient, cuisine or something random.

Programming languages: React, HTML, CSS, MaterialUI, APIs, LocalStorage

### Portfolio Example | https://tr-portfolio.netlify.app

 An interactive website where a user can toggle between multiple pages on various devices. An exercise in responsive design by using advanced CSS tools.

Programming languages: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap